hometalk.com 2013-02-02

# Hometalk Privacy Policy :: Hometalk

Last updated on June 20, 2012.

This privacy policy applies to the Hometalk Web sites. If users have questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, please contact us first at [privacy@hometalk.com](mailto:privacy@hometalk.com).

**Registration and Service Professional Enrollment**  
In order to participate in many of the site's features, a user must first complete a registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and E-mail address). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site, to allow other members of the site to contact you, and/or inform you about service professionals you have been matched with. By providing this information to us, or by submitting a service request, you expressly consent to being contacted by us and by our service professionals and providers via phone, E-mail or other reasonable means, at any of your contact numbers or addresses, in order that we may provide the services set forth on our Web site, service your account, reasonably address matters pertaining to your account or for other reasonable purposes related to our business.

**Getting Listed**  
To get listed on one of our site(s) we ask that you provide your Company Name, E-mail address and your name. We use this information to contact you regarding adding you to a list of contractors on our site. If you no longer wish to be listed on our site you may have your listing removed at any time by either calling the customer service department at (770)-504-5760 or E-mailing [service@hometalk.com](mailto:service@hometalk.com).

**Employment Application**  
If you choose to fill out the employment application on our site(s) we ask for certain personal information. The personal information we ask for is your name, phone number and E-mail address. We use this information to pass on to companies within your professional field who may be currently hiring.

**Hometalk Registration**  
In order to register for hometalk.com we ask you for your E-mail address and to create a username and password. We use this information for the sole purpose of creating your profile to allow you to start communicating with other users of the site and to find a contractor that best fits your needs.

Once you have signed up for www.hometalk.com, a profile is created for you. You have the ability to add a photo as your display image, add friends, communicate through private messages, and join groups. Please be aware that any personal information you choose to share within these features is viewed by other users of the site. is not responsible for the personal information you choose to share within the public area of the site. If you wish to delete your display image you may do so at any time by logging into your account and editing your profile.

**Service Request**  
We request information from the consumer in our service request interview process. A user must provide detailed information about the service requested. No financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date) is collected from the consumer. This information is used to match consumers with appropriate service professionals, so they can contact the user regarding his service request. The information may also be used to contact the consumer to verify or clarify his or her service request or for future communication related to home improvement services.

**Updating or Correcting Personally Identifiable Information**  
If your personally identifiable information changes or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it by making the change on our member information page, or by E-mailing our customer support at [info@hometalk.com](mailto:info@hometalk.com), or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. Within the "My Account" section on hometalk.com you have the ability to choose the types of notification you wish to receive, you may edit these at any time. You may also choose who gets to see when you are online and who gets to view your real name.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data tied to information about the user and stored on the user's computer. We use both session cookies, which terminate when a user closes his browser, and persistent cookies, which remain on the user's computer until manually deleted. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.  
We do not link the information we store in persistent cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf and to monitor certain pages of our Web site for the purpose of reporting Web traffic, statistics, advertisement "click-throughs," and/or other activities on our site. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous.

**Third Party Advertising**  
Some of our business partners may use cookies on our Web site (for example, advertisers). We have no access or control over these cookies once our business partners have been given permission to set cookies. This privacy statement does not cover the use of cookies set by third parties.

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the Web site, track the user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Special Offers and Updates**  
We send all new members a welcome E-mail. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services and special deals related to roofing and home improvement. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option not to receive these types of communications within the bottom of every E-mail sent by us to the user following the welcome E-mail (not including E-mails sent by the professionals, matched with the service request, over which we do not have control).

**Leads Notifications and Trial Lead Notifications**  
If a professional either signs up for our trial program or joins our service professional network, and elects to receive their leads via E-mail, that professional will receive multiple communications from us.

**Customer Service**  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via E-mail, fax, phone or mail, and we reply to user inquiries via E-mail or phone, or other reasonable means, in accordance with the user's wishes where applicable.

**Sharing Information to Provide Services and to Conduct Our Business**  
Hometalk does not share, sell, rent or trade Personal Information with third parties other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. When you submit information via our site(s), you authorize us to share this information with our network of service providers and partners in order to try to provide the services you request. For example, when an approved member of our service professional network accepts a lead from a registered user, and that user indicates the personal information he is willing to share so that the service professional can contact the user, such as telephone numbers and E-mail addresses, that information is shared with our service professionals who have accepted a service request lead. In addition, in the event we do not have any service professionals in your service area, we have other approved contractual partners that fulfill services requests, or that utilize their own service professionals to supplement our network, and we share your information with them, subject to contractual confidentiality restrictions, in order to attempt to provide the services requested. Though we strive to preserve user privacy, due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will always remain confidential. By way of example, we may disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a belief that such action is necessary or advisable to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, legal proceeding, process or investigation served on our business or Web site(s), or when we believe parties are misusing or attempting to misuse our Web sites or services, including but not limited to violating the law, committing fraud, deception, theft, attempting to harm or divert our business, engaging in threatening or inappropriate behavior or threatening to place, or placing themselves or others in danger. You should also be aware that courts of equity, such as U.S. Bankruptcy Courts, may have the authority under certain circumstances to require us to share or transfer your information to third parties. Finally, although we strive to protect your privacy, third parties beyond our control may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

**Blogs**  
If you use a blog, or group on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of the website, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit on the website.

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask for your friend's name and E-mail address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time E-mail inviting him or her to visit the site. stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time E-mail and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [info@hometalk.com](mailto:info@hometalk.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Feedback**  
If you choose to submit feedback on any of the sites, we will ask for your name and rating of the company in which you are providing feedback about. Your name will be displayed as you submitted it, if you do not wish to display your last name please just submit your first name or first name and last initial along with your feedback.

**Business Transitions**  
In the event goes through a business transition such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

**Links and Integrated Partnerships**  
Our Web sites contain links from and to other Web sites. Please be aware that the Hometalk Web sites are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other Web sites. We encourage our users to be aware of this when they leave our Web sites and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the Hometalk Web sites.

**Surveys & Contests**  
From time-to-time we may request information from users via surveys or contests such as name and E-mail address. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of our services and this Web site.

**Functionality of Web Site**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by E-mail, or by means of a notice on our homepage.

**Security**  
We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can E-mail us at [privacy@hometalk.com](mailto:privacy@hometalk.com).

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [privacy@hometalk.com](mailto:privacy@hometalk.com).  
Hometalk  
400 Lafayette St., 4th Fl  
New York, NY 10003  
Please feel free to contact us at (770)-504-5760.
